Thank you. All right. My name is Steve
McCown and I am a commissioner on the Utah
Privacy Commission. I'm also chief
architect of Anonomy Labs. And I'd like to
talk to you about surveillance and
tracking today and what SEDI does to get
in the way of that. Years ago, I worked
for the US Department of Energy as
basically a computer hacker. And one of my
assignments was to work on compromising
cell phones. Another part of my assignment
was what they call open source
intelligence. And this is the collection
and analysis of data gathered from open
sources, think internet, and in order to
produce actionable intelligence. And in
that capacity, I was able to be given
target sites and and pull together enough
information from the internet that
resulted in classified reports. So the
first I wanted to look and see when the
first open source intelligence was taking
place and this is January of 1862. A
publication called Harper's Weekly was
publishing articles about force movements
during the US Civil War. And as you can
see here, the text talks about a general's
expeditions and where the troops were
going, what assets he had. And while the
specific targets were secret, they also
were able to surmise where they were
going. They went so far as to draw
pictures of the target locations and the
forces attacking the other forces. In
modern times, let's talk about
surveillance for modern times. So how do
email marketers know when to call you? So
sometimes, and this happened to me
personally, I was reading an email and
within five minutes of reading the email,
I received a call from the sender of the
email and I engaged them in conversation
to find out how they were doing this.
Here's an example, one of many examples of
what we call tracking beacons. So what
they'll do, an email is simply like a web
page. It's an HTML-based email these days.
And they'll put a one-by-one pixel
transparent image on there. And for those
of you who know HTML, there's a little tag
called image that's supposed to load an
actual image. And instead of loading an
image, what it does is it contacts the
internet and pings a web service. And that
web service can do a variety of things and
you can add a variety of information,
username, email address, GPS location,
whatever you can get your handle, whatever
you can get a hold of and your email
client allows, you can then send that off.
So that's a modern example of open source
intelligence. And this leads us into what
we call surveillance capitalism, which is
a concept in political economics which
denotes the widespread collection and
commodification of personal data by
corporations. It's not limited to
corporations. Governments can do this too
and there can be collaboration between the
two. A couple of interesting points about
surveillance capitalism is that it
operates without meaningful mechanisms of
consent. It just happens to you. And you
can lose your self-determination through
the manipulation of advertising and other
practices that might happen as a result of
this. Duke University with West Point
University with the Army, they did a study
back in 2023 about data brokers and the
sale of data on US military personnel. So
data brokers using these kinds of methods
were able to collect sufficient
information that it became of interest to
foreign entities. And so as part of the
study, they were able to approach the data
brokers originating from either US domains
or .Asia domains and purchase information
on US service members and veterans. And
when they ordered in bulk, it was about 12
to 32 cents per record that you could get
on US military members. Think of all the
things we do on social media and how that
might be used as we heard this morning for
blackmail in order to invoke espionage.
This is a real problem yet it's also the
way the web kind of operates these days.
Their recommendations were federal privacy
legislation and also to restrict the
collection of data on current and former
military personnel. So how SEDI helps
protect our identity. So one of the
things, if you look back to SB 260, it
says in a couple of lines in here, the
state-endorsed digital identity enables an
individual to selectively disclose
elements of an individual's identity. So
taking the driver's license as an example,
when you go to a government entity, say
the Department of Motor Vehicles, you
don't really have an expectation of
privacy. You're going there to give your
information in order to get a driver's
license credential. So we don't really
have an expectation of privacy in that
regard just by the nature of that
interaction. However, when we go to the
bank, you don't need to give your height
and your weight and your donor status and
all that kind of stuff. And so you can
selectively disclose what the bank
requires. Then if you go shopping on
Amazon or somewhere other than payment
information, they need your name and they
need your address to ship whatever it is
you're buying. They don't need your
driver's license number. And so over the
summer, Apple has allowed MDLs to be used
for website logins. And that may create
some very unintended side effects about
the transfer of information.
Another aspect of SB260 is asserting with
zero correlation. So part of the one of
the lines in that bill says verify that
the individual's age satisfies an age
requirement without revealing the
individual's age or date of birth. So for
example, if I were to go to the Department
of Alcoholic Beverage Services, which is
where you buy liquor here in Utah, the
assertion you need to make is I'm 21 or
older. That's what's required in the law.
You don't have to give your name, your
address, or any other information. There
should be a way to give only the
information that is required. And that's
what SEDI is after. So when I go to a
concert at the Delta Center and I want to
use that neat fancy digital ticket, I need
to be able to assert that I purchased a
ticket that I am authorized to get in
having paid my money and so forth without
having to give all the other information
that may sometimes come with digital
credentials. I want this to be a process
of least disclosure, not full disclosure.
Now, when I go to the hardware store as a
veteran myself, I'm offered a 10% discount
and I get that by scanning everything on
my driver's license. That includes
obviously that I am a veteran, which is on
my status. It includes whether I'm a
donor, my height, my weight, my address,
all these things that are unnecessary for
that transaction. So SETI gives you a
choice. Here's a quote from the US Supreme
Court from back in 1995. It says,
anonymity is a shield from the tyranny of
the majority. It thus exemplifies the
purpose behind the Bill of Rights and the
First Amendment in particular. to protect
unpopular individuals from retaliation at
the hand of an intolerant society. Now,
whether you're on the left or the right,
this should resonate with you, maybe for
different reasons. But this is a really
important principle because if we don't
enable you to disclose only the
information that's required in an
untrackable sense in some situations, what
we will end up with is what's Scott
McNeely from Sun Microsystems said back in
1999, you have zero privacy anyway, get
over it. And so SEDI is giving you the
choice of what you disclose and when you
disclose it and they put that choice in
the hands of the holder. So that's what I
would hope that you would take away with
and you would go back to your respective
companies, departments and states and and
pose this to your constituents because we
want a private identity system that keeps
individuals safe. So thank you very much.
Max Max Max Max Max Max Max Max